# Tim Huitt

Broomfield, CO 80021 | 914-960-1960 timhuitt@gmail.com | timhuitt.com

#### **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

As an experienced Software Developer with a blend of self-taught expertise and formal education, I have been responsible for the professional development and deployment of multiple python and VBA applications, in addition to many personal and collaborative projects. I excel in leadership, team collaboration, and process optimization. My past experiences and commitment to continuous growth positions me as a valuable asset in delivering high-quality software solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Node.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap/Tailwind, Mongoose

Databases and other: MongoDB, REST, JSON, API

**Interpersonal:** Leadership, Team Guidance, Training, Project Coordination, Client Communication, Relationship Building, Management, Process Efficiency, Communication Skills, Problem-Solving, Self-Motivation, Adaptability

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Auto Component - GitHub | auto-component.com - React, Express, Node, Javascript, Tailwind, API

An npm published tool to streamline UI element creation in React projects through AI prompted generation

- Developed a custom input component that integrates with any project it's added to
- ❖ Designed the base prompt used for generating insertable outputs
- ❖ Incorporated seamless rendering of generated requests anywhere the component is placed

### Pawzbe - GitHub | pawzbe.com - Express, Node, JavaScript, EJS, Bootstrap, API

Pet centric social media app

- ❖ Collaborated with two amazing teammates to create a full CRUD application
- ❖ Integrated OAuth, Bootstrap, and various express frameworks
- ❖ Created RESTful routes while following MVC architecture guidelines

### Battleship - GitHub | App - Javascript, HTML, CSS

Submarine-themed Battleship Game, with a smart computer opponent.

- ❖ Built custom classes to handle grid creation and pop-up alerts
- Developed an advanced computer player that chooses cells based on previous hits
- Created a custom interface with a traditional Battleship/submarine theme

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Denver Data Analytics - Project Coordinator / Software Developer**

Denver, CO, 02/2021 - 08/2023

- Designed, developed and deployed multiple python/VBA applications, providing greater data/processing efficiency
- Worked with and managed a small group to collect and compile analytical data for private/municipal clients
- ❖ Deployed, operated, maintained, and oversaw the use of data collection equipment

#### **Lightshade - Assistant Manager**

Federal Heights, CO, 03/2019 - 01/2021

- ❖ Built multiple Excel applications to reduce time spent on redundant tasks
- ❖ Managed a retail establishment with 30+ employees and up to \$100,000/day in sales
- Directed and oversaw the operations, including cash/employee management, inventory/ordering, scheduling

# Merrill Lynch - Senior Financial Advisor

Ridgefield, CT, 08/2012 - 02/2018

- Created Excel applications to assist with managing client information, bookkeeping, and record keeping
- ♦ Managed investment portfolios, retirement and education accounts, insurance, and mortgages, for 30+ affluent clients
- ❖ Worked as a team of 4 advisors with over 200 clients and \$500M in managed assets

### **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly, Software Engineering** 

Remote, Certificate Received: 01/2024

Fullsail University, Computer Animation, Bachelor of Arts

Winter Park, FL, Degree Received 12/2011